Guide to the Theodore Thornton Munger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1817-(1845-1908) 1929; Series I; 2' 4" (7 boxes)
  - Family Correspondence
    - Munger, Rosa -- [Hoblitt, Margaret H.?] [Selden, Margaret H.], 1884-1899 (Box 7, Folder 218)
    - Munger, Rosa -- [Hoblitt, Suzan], 1884-1886, 1888 (Box 7, Folder 219)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Hume, Robert E., 1933 (Box 7, Folder 220)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Lyman, Delia W., 1890 (Box 7, Folder 221)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Merwin, May, 1885, 1887, 1890, 1894, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 222)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Munger, Cynthia Selden, 1867, 1874 (Box 7, Folder 223)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Munger, Elizabeth D., 1886 (Box 7, Folder 224)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Munger, Harriet, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 225)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Munger Family, 1905, 1906 (Box 7, Folder 226)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Seymour, George D., 1925 (Box 7, Folder 227)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Snow, Isabel D., 1884, 1885 (Box 7, Folder 228)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Steele, Carrie L., 1885 (Box 7, Folder 229)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Taft, Alexander T., 1903 (Box 7, Folder 230)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Taft, Arthur N., 1894, 1898, 1904-1906, 1908-1910, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 231)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Taft, Elizabeth T., undated (Box 7, Folder 232)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Taft, Theodore M., 1905 (Box 7, Folder 233)
    - Munger, Rosa -- Thompson, Helen E., 1886, 1888 (Box 7, Folder 234)
    - Munger, Rosa -- White, Andrew D., 1917 (Box 7, Folder 235)
    - Munger, Rosa -- B-W, 1888, 1890, 1893, 1895, 1897, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 236)
    - Phillips, Margie -- from Munger, Elizabeth Duncan, 1870, 1872, 1873, 1877 (Box 7, Folder 237)
    - Selden Family, 1817, 1823, 1877 (Box 7, Folder 238)
    - Unidentified (Box 7, Folder 239)
  - Correspondence of others
    - Bacon, Benjamin W. -- from F.E. Emrich, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 240)
    - Bacon, Benjamin W. -- from Arthur T. Hadley, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 241)
    - Bacon, Benjamin W. -- from John R. Thurston, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 242)
    - Bacon, Benjamin W. -- from Andrew Dickson White, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 243)
    - Baldwin, Prof. -- from S.E. Herrick, 1885 (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - Century Magazine, editor -- from [F.V.] Hayden, 1886 (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - Roswell-Smith -- from John Hay, undated (Box 7, Folder 246)
    - To E.P. Whipple from (J. Thompson), 1883 (Box 7, Folder 247)
- Writings, Speeches, And Research Materials, 1814, 1846, 1847, 1856, 1865-(1871-1906) 1924; Series II; 2' 6"
  This series consists of both manuscript and printed copies of books, articles, essays, reviews, and addresses, as well as the notes and research materials used in their preparation. Of special interest is a scrapbook containing printed articles, most of which are by Munger, on the "new theology" and the ecclesiastical conflicts it generated. There are also printed copies of Munger's reviews of books and articles, as well as the printed reviews of his own works.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by title or subject category.
  - "Alledged Cases of the Supernatural Outside of Revelation", [1865] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "The Alledged Economic Function of Vice", 1883 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Mrs. Eunice Anderson, Remarks at the funeral of, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Anniversary of 50 Years in the Ministry", [1906] (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The Appeal to Life, reviews of, 1887 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Art, lecture on, 1875 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Art, notes on, [1901] (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Articles, miscellaneous (by others than Munger), 1877-1924 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "The Atonement In Modern Religious Thought", 1900 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "The Bewilderment of Faith" (Nos. I & II), [1902] (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "The Blessings of Books", 1893 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "A Tribute to Bryant", 1878 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - The Buddhist Canon (Dhammapada), review of (incomplete), 1878 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Horace Bushnell, articles by, 1868 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Horace Bushnell, articles of others about, 1865-1902 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "Dr. Bushnell" (given in Oakland, Calif.), 1876 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Bushnell" (article for W.D. Grant), 1901 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - "Horace Bushnell", 1901-1902 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "Horace Bushnell", Addendum [Delivered at Church at which Bushnell was pastor], [1902?] (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Horace Bushnell, the Centenary of (manuscript and printed copies), 1902 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Horace Bushnell, "Christian Nurture," Notes on, [1879-1902] (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Horace Bushnell, "General Estimate," Notes on, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Horace Bushnell, lectures, notes for, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Horace Bushnell, notes on, [1846, 1856, 1899] (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Horace Bushnell: Preacher and Theologian, reviews of, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Horace Bushnell - The Work of Horace Bushnell (notes and draft), 1899 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - "Dr. Chalmers: A Preacher of the Day; A Pastor of All Days" [incomplete], 1879 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - "Thomas Chalmers. D.D., L.L.D.", 1879 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - "Change of Belief Without Loss of Power", 1896 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - "Changing Phase of Current Religious Thought", 1901 or 1902 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "Character through Inspiration", 1893 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - "Christian Education in Missionary Lands", 1872 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - "A Cock to Aesculapius", 1902 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - "The Communion", 1884 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    See also: "A Greater than Solomon"
  - "Comparison Between Early and Later Methods of Attaining Religious Character" (Missionary Concert Lecture), 1873 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - "Conflict of Science and Theology," notes on, 1892-1904 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Cortland Academy Commencement, 1847 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Prof. Dana, a tribute, [1895] (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - "Death or Sleep?", undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - "Dedication of Woodbridge Hall" (prayer), 1901 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - "The Divinity School and the University", 1902 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - "Henry Drummond", 1906 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - "Early Candle Light," notes for, [1902] (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - "The Edenic Period of Man", 1880 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Jonathan Edwards, notes on, [1889] (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - "Jonathan Edwards: the Voice of One Crying in the Wilderness", 1889 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - "Edwards and Mozoomdar", 1883 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - "Notes on 'Robert Elsmere'" (with fragment of a reply by John Burroughs), 1888 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - "Emerson," notes for, [1884] (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Essays for the Day "The Church" (notes & drafts), 1903 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Essays for the Day, "Introduction," "The Church" (notes & drafts), undated (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Essays for the Day, "The Interplay of Christianity and Literature" (Notes) Chapter II, 1893 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Essays for the Day, "Notes on the Scarlet Letter" (galley) Chapter III, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Essays for the Day, reviews of, 1901, 1904-1906 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Essays on the Sacred Language Writings, and Religion of the Parsis, review of, 1878 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - "Evolution and Apologetics," notes for, undated (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - The Evolution of Christianity, review of, [1903] (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - "Forty-Five Years in the Connecticut Pastorate", 1905 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - The Freedom of Faith, reviews of, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - "A French Revolution or Social Ostracism", 1905 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - William Lloyd Garrison, Printed extract from an address, 1879 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - "William Lloyd Garrison", 1879 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - General Conference of Congregational Churches of Rhode Island, [1870?] (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - "The General Convention and Missions", 1904 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Prof. Josiah Willard Gibbs, Prayer at the funeral of, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - "God's Pledge, Christ's Consciousness" (belief in immortality), 1904 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - "A Greater than Solomon", 1884 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - The Works of Thomas Hill Green, Review of, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - "Louis Harms of Herrmansburg - Hanover", 1866 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Harvard, Commencement Dinner (prayer), [1898] (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - "The Centenary of Hawthorne", 1904 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Hawthorne, notes on, 1901, 1902 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - The Heart of Things, notes for introduction, [1900 +] (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - Hebrews X:5 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - I Peter V:10 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - St. John VI: 47, 51-52, 56-57 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - I Timothy III: 15 (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - I Timothy VI: 19, (1889) (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - II Timothy II: 3, (1896) (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - II Timothy II: 3, (1893) (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - I Corinthians III: 16, (1896) (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - St. John I: 17, (1895) (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - St. John III: 11, 12, (1893) (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - St. John XI: 25-28, (1892) (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - St. Luke XV: 29, 30, (1890) (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - St. Luke XVI: 19, (1893) (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - St. Luke IX: 33, (1891) (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - St. Luke XV: 17, (1895) (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - St. Matt. XVI: 1-4, (1899) (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - St. Luke XV: 7, (1896) (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - St. Matt. XVIII: 9, (1896) (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - St. Matt. III: 1,2, (1895) (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - St. Matt. VII: 1,2, (1887) (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - St. Matt. XVI: 1-4, (1895) (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - St. Matt. XVIII: 23-, (1889) (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - St. Matt. IX: 36, (1894) (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - II Kings V: 17-19, (1896) (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Job II: 10, (1888) (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Psalms III: 5-7, (1894) (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Jonah, (1891) (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - "The Higher Realm of Happiness", 1905 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - "Hints on Exegitical Preaching" ( The Homiletical Magazine, Inc.), 1892 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - "Hints on the Use of the Bible in Preaching: extract printed in the Christian World, 1892 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Hospital Sunday, newspaper account of, 1885 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - "How a Barn Was Built in a Day: A Temperance Story", 1878 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - "How To Get On In the World:" I) Health, II) Education, III) Manners, IV) Religion, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - "How To Meet Skepticism in Our Congregations?", 1878 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - "Ideals Versus Excuses: A Lenten Word", 1903 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - "Immortality and Easter", 1897 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Immortality and the religious life, 1904 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - "Impressions of the Religious Condition of the North West Gained in a Journey over the N.P.R.R.", 1885 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - "Insurance," notes on, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - "International Christianity", undated (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - "The Interplay of the Christian Virtues", 1892 (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - "Introduction" (by T.T. Munger) for Telling Bible Stories, by Mrs. L.S. Houghton, 1905 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - William A. Ives, a tribute, 1888 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - "Father Keep: An Old-Time Hero", 1905 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Tredwell Ketcham, newspaper account of funeral, undated (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Lamps and Paths, reviews of, 1883 (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - "The Conscience of Abraham Lincoln", 1887 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - "The London Council and Calvinism", 1891 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - "The Influence of Longfellow on American Life", 1889 (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - "Longfellow: The Poet of the People", 1907 (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - "The Lords Prayer" Notes on, 1899 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - "Ignatius Loyola", undated (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - "Martin Luther", 1874 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - "George MacDonald's Work on the Miracles of Our Lord", 1871 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - "'Ian Maclaren' as a Theologian" (Original in "The Use of Money," 1886), 1897 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - "Man's Place in the Universe," notes on, [1889-1904] (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - "Man's Place in the Universe", 1904 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - "To Men in Trouble", 1884 (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - The Messages of Israel's Lawgivers, review of, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - "Minister or Doctor?", 1884 (Box 11, Folder 113)
    See also: "Then and Now"
  - "Minor Morals:" I) On the Care of the Person. II) Little Foxes. III) Good Manners. IV) The Betting Habit. V) Sowing Wild Oats. VI) Pluck., 1890 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - "Miracles," notes for, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - "Dwight L. Moody", 1900 (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Rev. Morley's Criticism of the Minister of North Adams Church, Munger's Letter to the Editor re. (original in "Hints on Exegitical Preaching" 1892), 1879 (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - Elisha Mulford, articles of others about, undated (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Elisha Mulford, notes on, [1900 or 1901] (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - "Personal Impressions of Dr. E. Mulford", 1886 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - "Reminiscences of Elisha Mulford", 1900 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - T.T. Munger -- articles, reviews of, 1898-1907 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - "Music, Heavenly Maid" (2 printed copies; 1 handwritten fragment), 1895 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - "My Christmas Mummy", undated (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - "Naming and Placing Books", [1902] (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - "Naming the Baby: a Holiday Story", 1883 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - "A Nation in Search of A Religion", 1901 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - "Nature and Art", 1891 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - "The Nature of Christ," notes for (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - "The New Relation of Woman to Society" (includes insert on Female Suffrage), 1881, 1895 (Box 12, Folder 130)
  - "The New Theology" (Prefatory Essay to "The Freedom of Faith"), 1883 (Box 12, Folder 131)
  - The New Theology and Church Polity (scrapbook) (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - "An Object Lesson in Religion", 1893 (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - "On Curing Henry", 1897 (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - On the Threshold, reviews of, 1880, 1881, 1887, 1891, 1892, 1898 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - "Organization as a Factor in the Ministry", 1904 (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - Edward John Phelps, memorial prayer, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - "Wendell Phillips", 1884 (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - "Wendell Phillips: a Reminiscene [sic] of Anti-Slavery Agitation", 1884 (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - "An American Citizen: the Late Henry L. Pierce", 1897 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - "The Place of Wrecks", 1902 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Plain Living and High Thinking, [1897] (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Plain Living and High Thinking, reviews of, undated (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - "A Plain Talk on Money" (incomplete), undated (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - "A Plain Talk on the Present Unrest in the Religious World", 1875 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - "A Plea for the Poets", 1896 (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Poem and Prayers, undated (Box 12, Folder 148)
  - Poem, "Deep Calleth unto Deep", undated (Box 12, Folder 149)
  - Poem, "Myself", undated (Box 12, Folder 150)
  - Remarks on Ex President Porter...", 1892 (Box 12, Folder 150A)
  - "Prayer and the Poets", [1902] (Box 12, Folder 151)
  - "Prayer on Decoration Day", 1901 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - "A Protest", 1902 (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - The Public Library, Report of a committee of nine to citizens of North Adams, concerning a Public Library (original newspaper clipping in "Sunday and the Railroads," 1881) (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - "Recent Changes in Christian Thought", 1895 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - "Recent Explorations in Africa as Bearing on Missions", 1879 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - "Re-Dedication of East Hartford", 1876 or 1877 (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - The Relation of Yale College to Religion in the Matter of Customs and Requirements, [1893] (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - "Religion's Gain From Science", 1889 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Reminiscenses, notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - "Reminiscenses" (manuscript and copy), undated (Box 12, Folder 161)
  - Reminiscenses, copy of letter to Ebenezer Munger, 1814 (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - "The Resurrection from the Dead", 1869 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - "Right to the Philippines" (newspaper account of speech), 1899 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - "The Rights of Dumb Animals", 1896 (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - "Frederick W. Robertson: the Preacher of Insight" (Six Principles), [1866?] [1892?] (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Frederick W. Robertson, essay on (read before the Winthrop Club), April, 1866 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Frederick W. Robertson (incomplete draft of "Preacher of Insight"), 1892 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Frederick Robertson, notes on, 1897, 1907 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - "Saint Elizabeth" (poem), 1885 (Box 13, Folder 170)
    [Original in "Personal Impressions of Dr. E. Mulford," 1886]
  - St. Paul and the Anti-Nicene Church, review of, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - "The Scenery of Homer and Vicinity", undated (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - "Sir Walter Scott's Journal", 1894 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - "The Journal of Sir Walter Scott" (inc.), undated (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - "John Seldon" (given at Seldon Family gathering), 1877 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Sermons, notes for, undated (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Sermons, reviews of, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 177)
  - "The Shadow of the Reformation", 1883 (Box 13, Folder 178)
  - "A Significant Biography" review of A.D. White's Autobiography, 1905 (Box 13, Folder 179)
  - "Some Aspects of the International Congregational Council", 1899 (Box 13, Folder 180)
  - "Some Probable Changes in the Twentieth Century", 1901 (Box 13, Folder 181)
  - "The Spiritual History of Maurice," notes for, undated (Box 13, Folder 182)
  - "Dean Stanley as a Preacher", 1872 (Box 13, Folder 183)
  - "Dean Stanley: the Apostle of Breadth" (handwritten and typed copies), 1894 (Box 13, Folder 184)
  - "Statement of Belief (made at North Adams, Mass.)", 1877 (Box 13, Folder 185)
  - "Stone Walls and Coefficients; Notes from an Upland Pasture", 1902 (Box 13, Folder 186)
  - "To a Stormy Petrel", 1882 (Box 13, Folder 187)
  - "Sunday in Route" (poem), 1885 (Box 13, Folder 188)
  - "The Sunday School: A Contributor to the Church", [1883] (Box 13, Folder 189)
  - "The Supreme Law of Society" (typewritten manuscript and printed excerpt), 1896 (Box 13, Folder 190)
  - "Reminiscenses of Dr. N.W. Tayler", 1908 (Box 13, Folder 191)
  - Major General Alfred How Terry, remarks at funeral of, 1890 (Box 13, Folder 192)
  - "Then and Now", 1884 (Box 13, Folder 193)
  - Theology Lectures, notes for, undated (Box 13, Folder 194)
  - "Treatment of doubts," notes for, undated (Box 13, Folder 195)
  - "Turning Points of thought and conduct", 1888 (Box 13, Folder 196)
  - "The Two Brooks," notes for, undated (Box 13, Folder 197)
  - Two Centuries of Christian Activity at Yale, review of (2 copies), 1902 (Box 13, Folder 198)
  - "Two Hundredth Anniversary of the Church in Haddam, Connecticut", 1900 (Box 13, Folder 199)
  - "The Unconquerable Habit", 1903 (Box 13, Folder 200)
  - "The Undertone" (poem) (original in "Edwards and Mozoomdar" etc.), 1890 (Box 13, Folder 201)
  - United Church, historical discourse (New Haven), 1892 (Box 13, Folder 202)
  - University Church, BiCentennial, notes for sermon, 1901 (Box 13, Folder 203)
  - "The Use of Money", 1886 (Box 13, Folder 204)
  - "The Use or Abuse of the World", 1901 (Box 13, Folder 205)
  - "Vitality, Character, Inspiration" (A Familiar: Talk to the Theological Students at Andover), 1880 (Box 13, Folder 206)
  - "The Vitality of Present Christianity", 1905 (Box 13, Folder 207)
  - Dean Wayland, a tribute, 1885 (Box 13, Folder 208)
  - "When Shall Discussion End?", 1883 (Box 13, Folder 209)
  - "Where We Are", 1902 (Box 13, Folder 210)
  - Yale Corporation, notes on, 1905 (Box 13, Folder 211)
  - Yale Lecture, notes for, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 212)
  - YMCA, letter to the editor, 1906 (Box 13, Folder 213)
- Sermons, 1858-(1880-1900) 1903; Series III; 3'9" (9 boxes)
  SERMONS are arranged by order of the Old and New Testament books from which the text of the sermon is taken. Each listing notes the text and the earliest date of the sermon. A small group of memorial sermons, sermons on political topics, and a series of ten sermons entitled "Christus Consolator" have been placed at the end of the series.
  - Genesis I: 1,2, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Genesis I: 14, 1888 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Genesis I: 1 & 27, 1899 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Genesis I: 31, 1899 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Genesis II: 2,3, 1858 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Genesis III: 22-24, 1888 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Genesis XVIII: 19, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Genesis XVIII: 19, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Genesis XXII: 1,2, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Genesis XXV: 27 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Genesis XXVIII: 10-13 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Genesis XXXII: 24, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Genesis XXXII: 24 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Genesis XLVII: 9, 1888 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Genesis L: 25 [2 copies], 1863, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Genesis L: 26, 1881 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Exodus XX: 5-6, 1889 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Exodus XXXIII: 18, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Exodus XIV: 15 (Christmas), 1862 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Exodus XIX: 16, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Numbers XIII: 10, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Deuteronomy III: 27, 1892 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Deuteronomy XXIV: 17-22, 1894 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Deuteronomy XXXIV: 5-6, 1881 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - I Samuel I: 28 - III: 1, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - I Samuel IX - X +, 1887 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - I Samuel XV: 22, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - II Samuel XXIII: 14-18, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - II Samuel XI: 14, 15 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - I Kings XIX: 4, 1890 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - I Kings XIX: 11-12, 1887 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - I Kings XIX: 18, 1898 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - II Kings II: 12, 1891 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - II Kings VI: 15-17, 1889 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - II Kings VIII: 13, 1892 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - II Chronicles V: 13, 14, 1866 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Nehemiah I: 1, 1887 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Nehemiah II: 17, 1862 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Nehemiah VIII: 9, 10, 1888 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Job I: 9, 1894 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Job II: 10, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Job XIV: 14, 1892 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Job XXXVIII: 1, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Psalms XIX: 7-8, 1900 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Psalms XXIII: 3, 1899 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Psalms XXV: 14, 1866 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Psalms XLVI: 1 (Children's Sunday), 1900 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Psalms LI: 6, 1887 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Psalms LXVI: 8-14, 1863 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Psalms LXXVIII: 72, 1865 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Psalms LXXVIII: 5-8, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Psalms LXXXV: 10, 14, 1897 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Psalms XLII: 11, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Psalms XLIII: 5, 1884 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Psalms XC: 5,6, 1892 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Psalms XCVII: 10-12, 1899 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Psalms CXIX: 19, 1885 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Psalms CXIX: 89-90, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Psalms CXXXIX: 1-8, 1889 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Psalms CL_____, 1859 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Psalms CXLX: 4, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Psalms XCVII: 2, 1881 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Psalms LXXVI: 10, 1881 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Proverbs III: 5,6, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Proverbs IV: 7, 1892 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Proverbs VIII: 19, 1873 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Proverbs IX: 1 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Proverbs XIII: 22, 1897 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Proverbs XXVII: 12, 1878 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Isaiah IX: 2, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Isaiah XI: 1-10, 1897 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Isaiah XXVI: 9, 1864 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Isaiah LX: 17, 18, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Isaiah LVII: 15, 1872 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Isaiah XLIV: 24-26, 1885 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Isaiah LVIII: 8, 1865 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Isaiah XL: 28-31, 1886 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Jeremiah XLVIII: 17, 1865 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Ezekiel X: 14, 1892 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Ezekiel XXI: 27, 1900 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Ecclesiastes I: 2/XII: 13, 14, 1895 (Box 16, Folder 28)